Jeff Gers Colorado, U.S.A. ♦ Cell: 303-803-5466 ♦ Email: jeffgersfx@gmail.com

Vision: User experience-focused full-stack QA Engineer with a passion for exploratory Mobile testing as well as recent experience with iOS and Web UI Automation test methods. I enjoy taking small companies to the next level by ensuring the quality and integrity of innovative and disruptive technologies while serving as a voice for the User.

Current Tools of The Trade (some level of experience with the following)

- Dev/QA Tools: XCode, Android Studio, Postman, Insomnia, Charles Proxy, Cypress.io, Tower, GitHub
- Experience with: Agile, Scrum, Kanban | Testing methods for mobile, web and API clients
- Recent testing of: Location services, camera/gallery permissions, push notifications/messaging, credit applications

Blinker, Inc (2015 - 2019) | Software QA Engineer

- Built and maintained a lightweight, yet extensive, native XCUITest automation framework for iOS application
 - Ran and debugged test suites during Releases
 - Used the framework as a tool for quickly getting into particular application flows
 - UI Automation is a supplement to my Functional testing techniques, I am a hands-on Tester by trade
- Contributed to a Cypress.io web automation framework.
 - Some experience building cypress.io tests with reusable methods for exercising various web flows
- Validated API endpoints and mutations using Postman and Insomnia
- Test and troubleshoot iOS, Android, web and responsive web applications as well as internal tools
 - Used native development solutions for debugging and automating
 - Consistently discovered high volumes of bugs that were the most impactful to the user keen eye for UI
- Helped define specs, user experience, acceptance criteria, and contributed to prototypes for new functionality
 - Vocal member during elaborations who forced teams to think critically about user experience
- Key contributor to weekly release management process of Mobile products
 - o Implemented the process of running iOS automation suite against releases
 - o Reduced RC test cycle time from 3-5 days of manual testing to 1 hour of automated testing
 - o Assisted with build management re: HockeyApp and distribution of apps for internal testers
- Worked with Support and Tech Operations teams regularly
 - Assisted with reproducing difficult customer issues and escalation for triage
 - Collaborated with Ops/Support team members to build better internal tooling to make their lives easier

Black Pixel (2013 - 2015) | Mobile QA Engineer (worked with multiple clients and internal Apple TV project)

- Client A (7 months) Integrated into client's team and tested a major rewrite of application
- Client B (6 months | two iOS apps) Brought in to help define QA standards for two iOS applications
- Client C (1 month) Small client with no internal QA. Helped to identify large quantity of bugs, quickly
- Client D (8 months | iPhone & iPad apps) Worked within small team of Black Pixel testers on client apps

Prior Professional Experience

- MOGL (2013) | Mobile QA Engineer
- Ubermind/Deloitte Digital (2011-2012) | Mobile QA Engineer
- GoDaddy, Inc (2010-2011) | QA Engineer
- Photobucket/Fox Interactive Media (2006-2010) | QA Engineer, Legal Compliance/Product Knowledge Manager

Education

- B.A. Visual FX-Motion Graphics, 2005: Art Institute of Colorado, Denver, CO (Graduated with honors)
- Photography-Electronic Media, 2000-2002: University of Colorado, Boulder, CO

Mobile App Contributions (since 2010):

Eaton PowerEdge, Every Body Walk!, MOGL, Starbucks, New York Times Now, New York Times Opinion, Storybird, Inspirato, Blinker